Guide to the Zygmunt Haupt Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 4: LITERARY WORKS, 4
  - Subseries F: The "Voice of America" and the United States Information Agency (USIA) broadcast scripts (1951-1960), F
    - January - March of 1953 scripts in Polish (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes "A Year in the Making" [1.1.53], "Prof. Lednicki's Lecture About Dostoyewski "[1.3.53], "Dwight D. Eisenhower " [1.20.53], "Polish Uprising of 1863 Against Russia" [1.23.53], "Biography of Professor Jan Dembowski" [1.30.53], "Name Day of Wieslaw Gomolka" [2.7.53], "Soviet Deportations of Poles in 1940 - Dramatization [2.10.53?], "Mass Deportation of Poles by Soviets in 1940: I-II" [2.11.53-2.12.53], "Communist Editor in Trouble" [2.18.53], "Anniversary of Death of Zygmunt Krasinski" [2.20.53], "Stalin's Death" [3.6.53; 3.8.53], "Deportation to Siberia" [3.13.53], and "Congress of Christian Democratic Union" [3.14.53].
    - May - June of 1953 scripts in Polish (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes" Polish Constitution of May Third, 1791" [5.3.53], "Poet Krasinski Against Russia" [5.8.53; I-II June 1953], "Slowacki's Burial" [5.8.53], "Poet Mickiewicz Against Russia" [5.15.53; 6.19.53], "Battle of Monte Cassino" [5.18.53], "From Soviet Labor Camps to Monte Cassino" [5.18.53], "On Communist Cultural Campaign Week in Poland" [5.19.53], "Copernicus: 400 Years Since His Death" [5.24.53], "Death Anniversary of Historian Lelewel" [5.29.53], "Birthday of Poet Maria Konopnicka" [5.29.53], "The Ascent of Mount Everest" [6.2.53], "Sport Talk, The Ascent of Mount Everest" [6.4.53], "New York and Moscow Subways" [6.4.53], "Soviets Create Polish 'Patriots' 1943" [6.12.53], and "Soviets Liquidate Polish Home Army" [6.19.53].
    - July - September of 1953 scripts (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Includes "Fourth of July!!" [7.3.53], "Bastille Day" [7.14.53], "Battle of Grunwald" [7.14.53], "A Warning to Communists" [7.17.53], " President's Broadcast on Truce" [7.27.53], "Warsaw Uprising" [8.1.53], "Truce in Korea" [8.1.53], "Battle of Warsaw 1920" [8.15.53], "Soviet Succession of Power" [8.17.53], "I Was Captive in Korea" [8.19.53], "Students Congress in Warsaw" [8.27.53], "German Invasion of Poland 1939 [9.1.53?], "Soviet Invasion of Poland 9.17.39" [9.17.53; 9.28.53], "Korowicz" [9.26.53], and "Fourth Partition of Poland" [9.28.53].
    - October - December of 1953 scripts of broadcasts (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Includes "Historian Lelewel Buried in Wilno in 1929" [10.9.53], "Pulaski's Day Parade (F. Wazeter)" [10.11.53], "Martydrom of The Church In Poland" [10.17.53], "Soviet Elections in Poland, October 1939" [10.23.53], "All Souls Day" [11.2.53], "Polish Youth Thinks Independently" [11.9.53], "Rebirth of Poland Day, 11 November 1918" [11.11.53], "Stefan Zeromski Anniversary" [11.20.53], "Lwow Anniversary of 1981" [11.20.53], "Adam Mickiewicz - Death Anniversary" [11.27.53], "Polish XVIII Century Writer Against Russia" [11.27.53], and "Death Anniversary of Poet Slowacki" [12.22.53].
    - 1953 scripts of the broadcast series, such as "Expansion of Polish Culture", "Polish Free Periodicals"(reviews), "Palomar" (I-III), "We Read What We Please", and "Science in Free Poland". (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 1953 scripts of broadcast series called "Polish Nation Versus Soviets" (I-XXXVII). (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1953 scripts of broadcast series called "Polish Nation Versus Soviets" (I-XXXVII). (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Dateless scripts, perhaps from 1953 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      includes "Forbidden in Poland - Malaczewski", "Soviet Subjugation of Eastern Poland", "TVA and Missouri Basin Development", "Dzierzynski", "Lyceum of Krzemieniec Founded", "Zolkiewski Occupying Kreml in 1610", "Pilot Jazwinski on Soviet Lies", and "Korowicz Press Interview on Forced Labor".
    - March - July scripts of 1954 Among them "33rd Anniversary of Polish Constitution of March 17, 1921"[3.7.54], "Polish Easter" [4.17.54], "Polish Constitution of May 3rd 1791" [5.3.54],"Tenth Anniversary of Monte Cassino" - 2 copies [5.18.54], "Rally of Polish Communist Writers in Warsaw" [6.13.54], "The Trial of 16 Polish Underground Leaders in 1945" [6.21.54], "Versailles Treaty" [6.25.54], "Fourth of July!!!" [7.4.54], and "Tenth Anniversary of Warsaw Uprising" [7.31.54]. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Among them are "33rd Anniversary of Polish Constitution of March 17, 1921"[3.7.54], "Polish Easter" [4.17.54], "Polish Constitution of May 3rd 1791" [5.3.54],"Tenth Anniversary of Monte Cassino" - 2 copies [5.18.54], "Rally of Polish Communist Writers in Warsaw" [6.13.54], "The Trial of 16 Polish Underground Leaders in 1945" [6.21.54], "Versailles Treaty" [6.25.54], "Fourth of July!!!" [7.4.54], and "Tenth Anniversary of Warsaw Uprising" [7.31.54].
    - August-September of 1954 scripts in Polish (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Includes "American Congress on Warsaw Uprising in 1944" [8.8.54], "Anniversary of The Battle of Warsaw 1920" [8.14.54], "Annual Convention of American Council on Polish Cultural Clubs" [8.14.54], "The Battle of Warsaw 1920" [8.15.54], "Klimowicz and Panufnik Story in NYT" [8.23.54], "Soviet-NAZI Plot and Aggression Against Poland in 1939" [8.23.54], "So Called Polish-Soviet Friendship Month Begins" [9.11.54], "Inauguration of So Called Polish-Soviet Friendship Month" [9.12.54], "Soviet Invasion of Poland in 1939" [9.17.54], "American Airmen Over Warsaw 10 years Ago" [9.18.54], "Panufnik Story in NYT" [9.26.54], and "Fourth Partition of Poland in 1939" [9.28.54].
    - Four scripts of the broadcast series "Review of The Free Polish Literary Periodicals" [perhaps from October 1954]. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - October - December of 1954 scripts in Polish (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Includes "The Fall of Warsaw in 1944" [10.2.54; 10.3.54], "Pulaski's Day Parade" [10.3.54], "Election Day" [11.2.54], "Polish Independence Day" [11.11.54], "In Memoriam of Tomasz Arciszewski" [11.25.54], "Thanksgiving Day" [11.25.54], "Polish Uprising of November 1830" [11.29.54], "Escape Into Freedom" [12.8.54], "Polish Christmas Eve" [12.24.54], and "Nativity and Adam Mickiewicz" [12.25.54].
    - Dateless, but most likely 1954 scripts (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Among them are "Peace Treaty of Riga 1921", "Kosciuszko Insurrection of 1794", "Katyn Massacre".
    - January - March of 1955 broadcasts scripts (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Includes "A Year in the Making" [1.1.55], "Soviet Army in Warsaw 10 Years Ago" [1.17.55], Polish Uprising of January 1863" [1.23.55], "Adam Mickiewicz - Hundred Years Anniversary" [1.25.55; 1.26.55; 2.22.55; 3.15.55], "Lincoln's and Kosciuszko's Birthday" [2.12.55], "Abraham Lincoln" [2.12.55], "Interview with Andrzej Panufnik I-IV" [2.21.55; 2.22.55; n.d.; n.d.], "Mass Deportations of Poles by Soviets in 1940 -II-IV" [3.4.55; 3.11.55; 3.12.55], "One Hundred Years of Polish Bible of Queen Zofia" [3.13.55], and "Soviet Writers and 'The Thaw'" [3.14.55].
    - April - May of 1955 broadcasts in Polish (some with no specific dates) (Box 14, Folder 9)
      "Adam Mickiewicz - Hundred Years Anniversary -VI, X" [4.4.55; 5.28.55], "Resurrection Day and Messianism of Adam Mickiewicz" [4.9.55], the only script in English from [4.18.55], with Billboard Page, "Nagy in Budapest, and Jozwiak in Poland Replaced", "Eisenhwer and Dulles on Bundung Conference", "Pope Pius Venerates New Martyrs", "Einstein Is Dead", "15th Anniversary of Katyn Wood Massacre", "American Includes "Democracy and the Federal Tax System"; "Poles in Buffalo Will Pay Tribute to Mickiewicz" [4.22.55], "'Life' on Poles in USA" [4.23.55], "'Socrealism'- Communist Political Compulsion in Art" [4.23.55], "Polish Constitution of May the 3rd" [5.3.55], "American Congress Regards Poland's Constitution Day" [5.4.55], "In the Eve of Polish Constitution Day" [5.3.55], "Anniversary of Foundation of University of Cracow" [5.14.55], "Eleventh Anniversary of The Battle of Monte Cassino" [5.18.55], "'Animal Farm' Revisited" [8.18.55], "Burial of Poet Slowacki in 1927" [5.27.55], and "Mickiewicz Celebration in Alliance College" [5.29.55].
    - June - August of 1955 broadcasts (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Includes "Poles in American Labor Service (Oddzialy Wartownicze)" [6.19.55], "Treaty of Versailles Anniversary" [6.19.55; 6.28.55], "Anniversary of the Battle of Gettysburg" [7.1.55], "Adam Mickiewicz - Hundred Years Anniversary-XI-XV, XX" [7.2.55; 7.11.55, 7.12.55; 7.30.55; 8.2.55; 8.28.55], "Fourth of July" [7.4.55], "U Nu in America" [7.6.55], "Before the Youth Festival in Warsaw - I, II, IV" [7.12.55; 7.19.55; 7.20.55], "Adam Mickiewicz Centennial in Cambridge Springs - II- Interview with Arthur Coleman" [8.3.55], "Adam Mickiewicz Centennial in Cambridge Springs - III - Interview with Cenzor Boleslaw Gunther" [8.5.55], "Rally of Polish Art Clubs in Buffalo" [8.8.55], and "Veterans of Polish Home Army in US Offer Holy Image to the Church in Mexico City" [8.8.55].
    - September-October of 1955 scripts of broadcasts (Box 14, Folder 11)
      "Gomulka Deposed Seven Years Ago" [9.9.55], "Interview with Wladyslawa Podkomorska, Delegate from Milwaukee" [9.26.55], "Interview with Boleslaw Gunthe, Cenzor of the Polish National Alliance" [9.26.55], "Interview with Mrs. Maria Sokolowska, Secretary of Organizing Committee of Sejm of PNA" [9.28.55], "On Soviet-Polish Friendship Month" [10.7.55], "Interview With Mr. Burke, Washington Representative of the Congress of Polish Organizations in the USA" [10.24.55], "Mickiewicz Centennial in American Press" [10.27.55], "10th Anniversary of Polish Peasants Leader Witos" [10.31.55].
    - November - December of 1955 pieces of broadcasts, mostly on Mickiewicz Centennial (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Includes "All Souls Day in Poland" [11.2.55], "Controversy over Wazyk's Poem for Adults" [11.7.55], "Interview with reverend Wladyslaw Sledz from St. Paul" [11.9.55], Poland's Independence Day" [11.11.55], "UNESCO Honors Mickiewicz" [11.15.55], "Vice-president Nixon on Mickiewicz Centennial" [11.7.55], "Adam Mickiewicz: Hundred Years Anniversary - XVI - Centennial Commemoration at Hunter College in New York" [11.21.55], "Adam Mickiewicz: Hundred Years Anniversary - XVII - Centennial Commemoration at Hunter College in New York" - three copies [11.21.55], "Adam Mickiewicz-Hundred Years Anniversary, from Pan Tadeusz" [11.24.55], "Poland and the Power of Poetry: Adam Mickiewicz Centennial" [11.25.55], "All Souls Day in Poland" - two copies, slightly different with a master cover sheet for foreign language recordings [11.26.55], "Poland's Greatest Poet: Adam Mickiewicz: in Commemoration of the Centenary of His Death (11.26.1850] [11.26.55], "Adam Mickiewicz - Hundred Years Anniversary - XXV - Death of the Poet" [11.26.55], "One Hundred Twenty Fifth Anniversary of Polish Uprising of 1830" [11.29.55], "Mickiewicz Centennial in Polish American Press" [11.29.55], New Translations of Mickiewicz in America" [12.5.55], "Mickiewicz Commemoration in Baltimore" [12.6.55], "Adam Mickiewicz - Poem Tenth" [12.20.55], "Christmas Eve in Poland" [12.24.55], and "Three Hundred Years Since the Siege of Czestochowa", [12.25.55].
    - Series of scripts called "Bolshevization of Polish Culture", broadcasted between [6.16.55] and [3.22.56]. (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - January - April of 1956 scripts (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Includes "Porgy and Bess Visits Poland" - two copies [1.14.56], "Poland's Uprising Against Russia in 1863" [1.22.56], "Woodrow Wilson Death Anniversary" [2.3.56], "Birthday of Tadeusz Kosciuszko and Abraham Lincoln" [2.12.56], "Life in America - III - Poles Attracted in New World" [3.22.56], "Cultural Life in America - VI - Nobel Prize Winner - William Faulkner" [3.27.56], "New Book of American Nobel Prize Winner, Pearl Buck" [4.10.56],and "Culture in Present Day Poland" [4.19.56; 4.26.56].
    - May - September of 1956 scripts (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Includes "Culture in Poland - the Cracow University Anniversary" [5.10.56], "Battle of Monte Cassino" [5.18.56], "The Book of the Justice Douglas on His Russian Journey" [6.11.56], "Jan Lechon in Memoriam" [n.d.], "Paderewski - Death Anniversary" [6.29.56], "Fourth of July" [7.4.56], "American Literature - O'Connor's 'Last Hurrah'" [8.1.56], "Color in Chicago Convention" [8.15.56], "Labor Day in America - Dramatization" [9.2.56], "Art in America - No.1 - the MacDowell Colony" [9.12.56], "Report from New Hampshire - Mount Washington Weather Observatory" [9.13.56], and "(...?) Peabody in the Museum of Salem" [9.15.56].
    - October - December of 1956 scripts (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Includes "(...?) The World of Mathematics" [10.2.56], "The Souls Day" [1.1.56], "Poland's Independence Day" [11.11.56], "Henryk Sienkiewicz - Three Anniversaries" [11.15.56], "(...?) Anniversary" [11.22.56], "Adam Mickiewicz-101st Anniversary of His Death" [11.26.56], "Anniversary of Uprising of November 29th, 1830" [11.29.56], "Christmas in Washington D.C." [12.24.56], and "Christmas in USA" - two copies [12.25.56].
    - Broadcast series called "Culture in Present Day Poland" [5.3.56; 5.17.56; 5.24.56]. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Broadcast series called "Frontiers of Knowledge", 6th and 12th - two copies [10.8.56; 12.17.56]. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Broadcasts called "American Panorama" (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Includes "American Music" [5.22.56], "Stephen Collins Foster"[n.d.], "Hawaii" [54 or 56], "American Composers - Aaron Copland" [n.d.], "Song of the Mississippi" [54 or 56], "Jazz was Born in New Orleans - American Panorama" - two copies [54 or 56], "Kitty Hawk, Wright Brothers' Memorial" [n.d.], and three completely unreadable copies of unidentified scripts.
    - Series of scripts of "American Literature", broadcasted between May and October of 1956 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Includes " E.A. Poe and the Detective Story" [5.23.56], "Emily Dickenson and Poetry" [n.d.], "Thorfau and Transcendentalists of New England" [8.29.56], "Nathaniel Hawthorne and Salem" [9.5.56], "The World of Science Fiction" [9.19.56], "The Art of Edgar Allan Poe" [10.3.56], and "Last Sixty Years as Seen by NYT Book Review" [10.10.56].
    - Broadcast scripts "Cultural Life in America" (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Includes "Reading Habits" [3.5.56], "Nobel Prize Winners" [3.8.56], "Other Nobel Prize Winners" [3.14.56], "National Gallery in Washington" [3.18.56], "Nobel Prize Winner - Ernest Hemingway" [3.21.56],"Nobel Prize Winner - William Faulkner" [3.27.56], "American Born T.S. Eliot" [4.11.56], "Literary Magazines in America" [4.11.56], "Nobel Prize Winner: Play Writer Eugene O'Neill" [4.18.56], and " Nobel Prize Winner - Sinclair Lewis" [4.25.56].
    - 1957 broadcast scripts (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Includes "Reportage from Inauguration Parade" [1.21.57], a piece on Jozef Hoffman, Polish pianist, the title unidentified [3.18.57], "American Reading - a Book on Pearl Harbor by Walter Lord" [4.9.57], "Reportage from Architects Centennial Meeting in Washington" [5.13.57], "O'Neill's 'Long Day's Journey Into Night" [5.14.57], "Leopold Staff, Polish Poet" [6.6.57], unidentified, unreadable script dated [6.13.57], "National Geophysical Year" [7.1.57], "Fourth of July - Dramatization" [7.4.57], "The 37th Anniversary of the Battle of Warsaw" [8.15.57], and "1957 Christmas Show - 'Amahl and the Night Visitors' of Menotti" [n.d.].
    - Dateless scripts from 1957, such as: "Feature on Ford Foundation", "The World of Jazz", and "On the Eve of Cleveland Orchestras' Visit to Poland". (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of Broadway musicals (some are dateless) (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Includes "Broadway at the End of the Theatrical Season" [7.8.57], unidentified pieces about the musical "Oklahoma" [8.29.57], "The Most Happy Fella" - two copies [9.5.57], and scripts "Carousel" [9.26.57], "South Pacific" [10.3.57]. Also, there are dateless pieces, such as "The Pajama Game", "Showboat", "Happy Haunting" - two copies, "My Fair Lady"," The King and I", and "Annie, Get Your Gun".
    - February - July of 1957 scripts of broadcast series called "American Literature" (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Includes "Erskin Caldwell" [2.13.57], "Francis Scott Fitzgerald" [2.20.57], "Henry Wadsworth Longfellow - 150th Anniversary of Birth" [2.27.57], "Poetic Renaissance" [3.6.57], "Reportage from the Library of Congress - Interview with poetry Consultant, Randall Jarrell" [3.27.57], "Reportage from the Hunter College in New York - Interview with Clark Mills, the Editor of Mickiewicz's Translations by American Poets" [4.3.57], "Literary periodicals" [5.8.57], "American Literary Periodicals Abroad" - two copies [6.12.57], "Henry James" [7.3.57], "Sholem Asch - Obituary of a Novelist (...)" [7.10.57], "Poets in Landscape" by Gilbert Highet" [7.17.57], and "Polish Poets in Chicago on American Poets" [7.31.57].
    - August - December of 1957 scripts of a broadcast series called "American Literature" (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Includes "New Direction in Prose and Poetry" [8.7.57], "Short Story" [8.8.57], "Forerunners or Present American Prose Writing - Stephen Crane, Frank Norris, Jack London" [8.14.57], "Forerunners or Present American Prose Writing - Theodore Dreiser" [8.21.57], "Mark Twain's Huckleberry Finn" [n.d.], "Wallace Stevens and his Opus Posthumous" [8.28.57], "'Our Town' by Thornton Wilder" - two copies [n.d.], "Interview with Prof. L. Krzyzanowski of Columbia University on Study of Contemporary American Literature in the Curriculum of American Universities" [9.4.57], "American heritage" [9.18.57], "'The Glass Menagerie' by Tennessee Williams" [1957?], "'Letter from America: Rediscovery of O'Neill' by Kazimierz Wierzynski" [n.d.], and "Polish Poets Round Table Discussion on Carl Sandburg" n.d.].
    - February - September of 1957 scripts of a broadcast series called "America Is Reading" (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Includes " Biography of Joseph Conrad" [2.19.57], "Poems of Marianne Moore" [2.26.57], "Oregon Trail" [3.5.57], "The National Book Awards" [3.26.57], "Chris Morley" [4.2.57], "Science Fiction" [4.23.57], "The Lion and the Throne" [5.7.57], ], "Philip Wylie: Innocent Ambassador" [ 6.4.57], "A Guide to Summer Reading" [6.11.57], "Eudora Welty" [6.18.57], "Van Wyck Brroks and the Role of the Writer" [6.19.57], "Joseph Conrad Appraised in America" [7.2.57], "Selden Rodman's 'One Hundred American Poems'" [7.16.57], "Kenneth Roberts Dead" [7.24.57], "'Battles That Changed History' by Fletcher Pratt" [8.6.57], "'By Love Possessed' by James Gould Cozzens" [8.27.57], and "Books on Civil War" [9.10.57].
    - American Music broadcast series (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Includes "Gian-Carlo Menotti" [4.28.57?], "Charles Ives, Roger Sessions, and Virgil Thomson" - two copies [5.16.57], "Aaron Copland" [n.d.], and "Leonard Bernstein" [n.d.].
    - Two copies of the broadcast script "How 'The Star-Spangled Banner' Was Born - Dramatization" [7.4.60].Water damaged, but readable. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Dateless broadcast pieces (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Includes "Omissions in Official History of Polish Communist Party" "An Review with a Polish Refugee Who Settled Down in USA, Kazimierz Mikuszewski - X", "Christmas in XVIIth Century Poland", "Story of Jan Hajdukiewicz", "I Confess - I-V", "Polish Easter - Dramatization" (ink stained, only a small part of the text is readable).
- Series 5: WRITINGS BY OTHERS, 5
  - Photocopies of poetry by Robert Pack, Norma Farber, Spencer Brown, Louis Simpson, Joseph Langland, five poems of Casimir Wierzynski traslated by various {American?) poets, Adam Czerniawski's translation to English of two Polish poems by Zbigniew Herbert and Tadeusz Rozewicz. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Typescripts of various excerpts and articles by other writers (from Harper's, Saturday Review, etc.). (Box 16, Folder 1112)
    Some of them have the title "Working Copy". Among them are: " Notes: Contemporary American Poetry", "Wake Up, Stupid" by Mark Harris, "Contemporary Art (...)" by Lee Steinberg, "High School Students Speak Out" by David Mallery, "A Christmas Memory" by Truman Capote, "Five poems by Robert Frost", "The Brain vs. The Machine" by Joseph Wood Krutch, "Will Sucess Spoil The "Village Voice"?" by Mel Gussow, "Language Is The Concern of Every Human Being" by W. H. Auden, "After Civilization What?" by Kenneth E. Boulding.
- Series 6: MATERIALS ADDED TO HAUPT'S COLLECTION, 6
  - Biography related documents (Othertype 17, Folder 1)
    "Zygmunt Haupt (1907-1975): A Biographical Sketch" by Arthur Norris Haupt (son), and "Genealogical scheme of the [Haupt] family", compiled by Haupt's Polish relatives in the 1970s. The biographical sketch is based on conversations with Edith Norris Haupt (wife), information gathered from Polish relatives, personal memories, and research foundings by Aleksander Madyda (affiliated with Nicolaus Copernicus University, Torun, Poland)
  - Documents related to Haupt's writings (Othertype 17, Folder 2)
    Includes "Bibliografia tworczosci literackiej" [Bibliography of Writings] Zygmunta Haupta by Aleksander Madyda (1937-1989), "Aleksander Madyda's Bibliography of Writings by or About Zygmunt Haupt That Appeared in 1988 and After", and a review of a German edition of "Paper Ring" by Zygmunt Haupt, published in "Die Zeit" in February of 2004.
  - Miscelloneus: "Brief, Incomplete Catalog of the Zygmunt Haupt Papers (prepared in 2004 by Arthur Haupt) and Aleksander Madyda's comments on some materials in the Zygmunt Haupt papers. (Othertype 17, Folder 3)
    The collection was rearranged in 2008, so the catalog and some of Madyda's comments are not up to date anymore.
  - Two CD-Rs with Word files: "Zygmunt Haupt Material", sent to Stanford in August of 2008 by Arthur Haupt (duplication of content of 17.1., 17.2., and 17.3.), and "Zygmunt Haupt: Collected Works". (Othertype 17, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings with Haupt's published works. Also, "Kultura": 1987, no.11 (482), with Renata Gorczynska's article about Haupt. (Othertype 17, Folder 5)